

ONG JIA YING

Test Process & Equipment Engineer



+6016-5506865



jying1997@gmail.com



Block B, Sinaran Residence, 14110 Batu Kawan, Penang



Whatsapp me.

EDUCATION

B. Eng. (Hons) Electrical & Electronic

Universiti Tunku Abdul Rahman (UTAR) May 2016 - May 2020 CPGA: 3.69 (First Class) USSDC (soft skill): Merit

Foundation in Science

Universiti Tunku Abdul Rahman (UTAR) May 2015 - May 2016 CPGA: 3.68

PLKN (National Service Training Programme)

Kuala Nerang, Kedah Dec 2014 - Feb 2015 Member of marching drill formation.

SPM (Malaysian Certificate of Education)

SMK Gurun Dec 2014 Result: 8A. 2B

LANGUAGE

- English
- Mandarin
- Malay
- Japanese
- Hokkien

About Me

As an experienced test process and equipment engineer (5 years), I specialize in validating, implementing, controlling, and optimizing test process framework to ensure the reliability and performance of complex system. Besides that, I also have expertise in data analytic and coding.

WORK EXPERIENCE

June 2020 - present

INTEL TECHNOLOGY SDN. BHD

Module Engineer / Senior Test Process & Equipment Engineer

- Proven record of good performance:
 - Grade 3 (June 2020) → Grade 5 (April 2022) → Grade 6 (April 2024)
 - Awarded as Quality Hero on year 2022.
- Process/productivity improvements & Lean manufacturing:
 - Qualified test program to enable a feature which can save ~47%
 TTR on fail events.
 - Experimented & deployed continuous testing process eliminating
 ~40% capacity wastage.
 - Standardized PCO config, saving ~0.31 hrs of conversion time.
 - Implemented lean process for part replacement, improving efficiency & saving ~\$4.9k/year.
- Defect reduction / cost saving project & Quality control:
 - Coordinate & plan new part DOE, validation, implementation & monitoring which success resulted in < 1% fallout.
 - Analyzed data with Pareto technique & deployed new test, saved ~60% of expensive component replacement usage (~USD\$2.7K/unit).
 - Detected & recovered in-house quality issue, preventing escape to customer.
 - Deployed daily monitoring script to ensure the quality and process of the new part installation done correctly by manufacturing.

TECHNICAL SOFTWARE TOOLS

- Microsoft 365 Applications (eg: Excel, Word, PowerPoint)
- Generative AI (eg: ChatGPT, Copilot)
- Visual Studio Code / Visual Studio
- Spyder & Jupyter Notebook
- JMP
- PowerBI
- GitHub Desktop
- MATLAB
- MPLAB
- CICON PLC
- EDA (Electronic Design Automation)
- Bambu Lab
- Free CDA

PROGRAMMING LANGUAGE

- Python
- C/C++
- Bash commands
- JSL
- SQL
- HDML, CSS & Javascript

OPERATING SYSTEM

- Window
- MacOS
- Ubuntu (Linux)

TECHNICAL HARDWARE TOOLS

- Oscilloscope
- Multimeter
- Frequency counter
- Power supply (bench type)
- Torque screwdrivers & allen keys
- Soldering station
- Microscope / Magnifier

- Scripting & Data Projects & Machine Learning(ML):
 - Developed Python script to auto-summarize data, saving ~80% of RMA data prep work.
 - Analyzed, trained, and modelled predictive ML model achieving 90% accuracy & improving first pass yield by 20%.
 - Assisted in validating & providing data samples to retrain text bucket ML model for better accuracy.
 - Developed SQLpathfinder script for auto-triggered daily reporting, monitoring, and abnormality detection.
 - Developed a PowerBI dashboard, improving engineering reporting TPT by 50%.
- Excursion management, Leadership & Responsibility:
 - Willing to expand my scope and take ownership on more products.
 - Led & resolved excursions/interruptions with prompt 8D actions to prevent downtime and minimize impact.
- Product transfer, New product integration (NPI) & Outsource:
 - Delivered training & provided investigation finding during outsource Factory cert activities.
 - · Obtained NPI Factory cert & Transfer cert.
- Unit exit & Audit:
 - Cleared WIP, cycle count, compiled tool inventory for space & budget prep. Disposition & hands-on tools deinstallation for resale & reuse. Documents data mapping & retrieving for custom audit.

Oct 2018 - Dec 2018

TOP GLOVE SDN. BHD

Trainee (Industrial training / Internship)

 Project management, power distribution and protection design, vendor communication, site visits.

CERTIFICATES

- Six Sigma Yellow Belt.
- Advanced Python Scripting.
- Data Scientist Basic, Intermediate & Advanced.
- Microsoft Excel Intermediate to Advanced.
- Machine Learning A-Z: AI, Python & R.
- The Complete SQL Bootcamp: Go from Zero to Hero.
- Business Writing Skills for Operation Professional.
- Presenting to Influence.
- The Essentials of Finance and Accounting for Executives.
- ATM Data Fluency Level 3: Advanced

REFERENCES

Goh Fong Hsia

Intel | Module Engineering Manager

Phone: +6012-4320859 **Email:** fong.hsia.goh@intel.com

Teoh Hooi Choon

Intel | Module Engineering Manager

Phone: +6012-7004986

Email: hooi.choon.teoh@intel.com





https://jying97.github.io/my_portfolio/

The information on my website closely mirrors my resume, but offers a more interactive experience.